要是你想穿得像个意大利窑姐儿
If you're going to dress like an Italian hooker,
至少也得是今年花红的打扮啊
at least let it be this year's Italian hooker.
她在说我们看起来很苗条
She's not telling us we look fat.
还真是一突破性进展啊
That's a major breakthrough.
如果你不想被羞辱
If you didn't want to be insulted,
那喊我来做什么
you wouldn't have invited me.
有人想来点香槟吗
Would anyone like some champagne?
-不用了  -三杯  谢谢
- No. - Yes, three glasses, please.
-妈  -是啊  这还不到午饭时间
- Mom. - Yeah, it's not-- it's not even lunch.
如果你们喜欢  那换含羞草[鸡尾酒]好了
If you'd prefer, I'll make it a mimosa.
-你觉得怎么样  -完美
- What do you think? - Perfect...
如果你是要去夜店的话
For a night on the town.
这适合穿来喂奶
Perfect for breast-feeding.
我心脏又感觉怪怪的了
My heart's doing that weird thing again.
跳动吗  是颗心脏都这样
Beating? That's normal for humans.
别这样  丽莎  就认真对待她一回
Come on, Lisa, take her seriously for once.
怎么  有问题吗
What? What is it?
我觉得你最好去趟医院
I think we need to get you to the hospital.
快让我试试
I'm dying to try it.
-没人打算告诉我  -嘘
- Is no one gonna tell me... - Shh.
多叫人高兴呀
How delightful.
我们为什么要来停尸房吗
Why we're in the morgue?
豪斯在躲一个人
House is on the lam from someone.
陶博赌是威尔森
Taub's got his money on Wilson,
但我肯定是卡迪
but I'm pretty sure it's Cuddy.
真是傻瓜的赌注  外头到处都是
Fool's bet. There's a whole world of
愤怒的病人  债主
angry patients, creditors...
她需要医生
She needs a doctor.
当然  不过不是我
Yes, just not me.
你母亲都六十五了
Your mom is a 65-year-old woman
高血压而已
with high blood pressure.
那巨红细胞性贫血是怎么回事
What about the macrocytic anemia?
只低于正常范围一点
Borderline,
这种测试结果几乎可以算是想象出来的病
which is the lab equivalent of imaginary, which,
她病史上的症状都这德性
by the way, matches the rest of her medical history.
你真觉得
You really think
她把自己吓成心房颤动了吗
she's psyching herself into atrial fibrillation?
那就给她找个心脏病医生
So get her a cardiologist.
你又不想拉我下水
You don't want me involved.
你自己都不想牵涉其中
You don't want you involved.
我从不理会的伦理道德
All that ethics stuff that I don't give a crap about
现在好像还有点道理啊
suddenly makes sense.
如果你感情用事
If you're emotionally invested,
就无法理性行事
you cannot make rational decisions.
你知道后果不堪设想
You know this would be a disaster.
这可是我母亲啊
This is my mother.
平板试验结果正常
Treadmill test went well--
没有出现胸痹或缺血性胸痛
no chest discomfort or ischemia.
心律失常应该会自行恢复
The abnormal rhythm will probably resolve itself,
不然  每天一颗小药丸将会控制病情
and if not, a daily pill will keep it under control.
稍候我会继续跟进
I will follow up later today.
这和我其它的病症有关联吗
Is it connected to my other symptoms?
什么其它的症状  妈妈
Which other symptoms, mom?
真怨不得她
Aye... Not her fault.
这个"医学院院长"的头衔
This "Dean of Medicine" stuff--
在各种派对上很抢眼
very impressive at parties.
但她都忘了怎样当个真正的医生
But she's forgotten how to be a real doctor.
我的病历上都写着呢
It's all in my file.
这里有十五年的门诊病历记录
There are 15 years of clinic visits in this file.
我不想太麻烦人
I don't want to be a bother.
但你不就是干这行的吗
But isn't this what you do for a living?
那么  我们要找出
So... we're looking for a disease
横跨十五年之久
that can last a decade and a half,
能引起便秘  痢疾  流感  感冒
causes constipation, diarrhea, flu, cold,
头晕  皮疹  背痛和关节痛
dizziness, rashes, back and joint pain,
"心脏感觉很奇怪"
"Heart feeling weird,"
"真皮感觉很松弛"
"Kishkes feeling wobbly,"
还有一次髋关节置换术
one actual hip replacement.
而多年的血液检查
And which has eluded detection by years of blood work,
X射线和核磁共振都查无所获
X-rays, and MRIs.
刚巧我正好想到一个
Well, one thing does pop to mind.
我们会继续观察
We'll monitor you,
并给你安排一次甲状腺测试
and we'll give you a thyroid test.
豪斯的小组会检查你的住所
And House's team will do a home search
是否存在环境毒素
for environmental toxins.
他看起来挺在行的
He seems to know his stuff.
怎么买不起合身的白大褂呢
How come he can't afford a coat that fits?
没有氡  霉菌  管道不含铅
No radon, no mold, no lead in the pipes.
好好  很好
Yeah, yeah, great.
有看到卡迪的高中年鉴吗
Have you seen Cuddy's high-school yearbook?
这明显跟这案子没关系
Okay, that is clearly not related to the case.
本来就不存在什么案子
There is no case.
卡迪不肯让豪斯看她的年鉴
Cuddy won't let House see the yearbook,
他觉得是因为她有所隐瞒
so he figures there's something to hide.
有什么好猜的  不就是
Any guesses? It's clearly related
标准的书呆子那档子事嘛
to being a giant teenage dork.
而你觉得我深有体会
So you thought I'd have some insights.
不  没有
Oh, no, no.
-我不是这个意思  -没事儿
- I didn't mean. - Relax.
我当过返校节小丑[相对于返校节女王]
I was crowned homecoming geek.
我觉得你一定有所体会
I'm sure you can relate...
你也认识不少书呆子嘛
Because you knew some dorks.
我以前是学生会主席  还是班长
I was the class president and head boy at--
啊
Aah!
这  这是卡迪的母亲吗
Is that -- Is that Cuddy's mom?
是她的某个部位
Certain parts of her...
以及神秘西班牙猛男的某个部分
And certain parts of some muscular Hispanic gentleman.
我们要考虑性传播疾病吗
Should we consider STDs?
光是看这些照片我就像被传染了一样
I think I just caught one looking at these photos.
"阿扎康"是什么意思
What does "Azarcon" Mean?
我
I--
意味着这是件真正的病例
It means we might have an actual case.
这是用来治疗胃部问题的墨西哥草药
Mexican herbal medication for stomach problems,
如果铬酸铅
but only in the sense that lead chromate
算毒药草的话
is an herband poison is a medication.
我会开始静脉注射螯合疗法  谢谢
I'll start a chelation I.V. Thank you so much.
你看  这也没有到灾难的地步嘛
That wasn't too much of a disaster, was it?
我说
You know...
他们在她家还发现了别的东西
That's not the only thing they found in her home.
别是我的年鉴
Not my yearbook...
不是
Nope.
不过是些能引起
Just some stuff that could cause
严重恶心以及性功能障碍的事
severe nausea and permanent erectile dysfunction...
而你母亲帮了点小忙
And which proves that your mom is doing the help.
就她日记所述  是个叫荷西的承包商
According to her diary, it's some contractor named Jesus...
当然  这最初是犹太人的名字  不过
Which, granted, was originally a Jewish name, but...
行啊  老妈
Go, mom.
那个  你怎么会使用墨西哥的民间疗法
So... why were you taking a Mexican folk remedy?
一个朋友在用的
A friend uses it.
一位朋友  妈
A friend? Mom...
就算是出于医学原因  你也该告诉我的
Just for medical reasons, you should have told me.
如果你还很有性趣
If you're sexually active--
在我这般年纪  他才是主动的那个
At my age, he's more the active one.
妈妈有风流韵事呢
Mom's having a fling.
我知道
I know.
什么
You do?
五年来  她一直给我提供扫兴的劝告
She's been giving me lousy advice about it for five years.
-我有生理需求  -他是有妇之夫
- I have physical needs. - He's a married man, mom.
她不想跟他亲热
She doesn't want sex with him.
我可愿意跟他滚床单呢
I do want to have sex with him.
你倒是告诉我  对谁不利了
Tell me, who's being hurt?
慢点  有五年了
Hold on. Five years?
-你为什么不告诉我  -我不知道
- Why didn't you tell me about it? - I don't know.
我们没到能交心的地步吧
We don't have that kind of relationship.
这让你很惊讶吗
Does that really surprise you?
你不租房子吗
You're not renting?
你说有两个人会帮你搬东西的
You said you had two guys helping you move.
他们抽不开身
They couldn't get out of work.
我得尽量节省开支
I'm trying to economize.
这家宾馆更实惠
This hotel's cheap.
好啊
Hi.
不好意思  我就是送几封信过来
I'm sorry. I just wanted to drop off some mail
顺便跟你谈点事
and talk to you about something.
进来吧
Of course.
瑞秋
Rache...
克里斯  我不是为这个来的
Chris, that's not why.
我们得向前走了
We got to move on.
这话什么意思
What does that mean?
你已经向前走了吗
Have you moved on?
和谁  那个菲尔吗
With who? Is it Phil?
我不想谈这个
I don't want to talk about this.
我知道你现在手头有点紧
I know that you're worried about money.
-你想扯开话题  -对
- You're trying to change the subject. - Yeah,
我刚才说过
which you could have gleaned from,
"我不想谈这个"
"I don't want to talk about this."
我给你争取了一次试用机会
I got you a tryout
兼职法律诉讼的医学顾问
to be a part-time medical consultant on lawsuits.
等等  跟你兄弟共事吗
Wait, with your brother?
我们上回见面的情形你都忘了吗
Have you completely forgotten the last time I saw him?
都是五年前的事了
Yeah. That was five years ago.
杰米那时刚得知你背叛我
Jamie had just found out that you'd been cheating on me
勾搭你合伙人的女儿
with your partner's daughter.
他当时有点反应过度了  我
So it's a little overreaction. My--
他打断了我的鼻子还说我
He broke my nose and then called me
是他这辈子见过最差劲的人
the most horrible person he's ever met.
他不该打断你鼻子的
He shouldn't have broken your nose.
现在  短信  来电和邮件
You know, texts, calls, and emails
一个神奇的小机器就都有了
all go to the same magic device these days.
而你只需择其一发一条就行了
You only got to send one.
那这就更奇怪了
Then it's even weirder
从楼上下来怎么要花你那么久的时间呢
it took you so long to get down here.
这个嘛  是个令人抓狂的奥秘
Yeah, that's a crazy mystery.
好像我没有个部门要管理似的
It's not like I got a department to run.
另一台神奇小机器告诉我  铅中毒
This other magic device tells me that lead poisoning
-不会引起我所有的症状  -没错
- wouldn't cause all my symptoms. - True.
但它会引起其中5%的真实症状
But it could cause the 5% that are real.
你认为我是疑病症患者
You think I'm a hypochondriac?
不如我这么回答你吧  或许你只是
Well, let me answer this way-- maybe you're imagining
在想像我认为你是疑病症患者
that I think you're a hypochondriac.
看  我的手开始颤抖了
Look, my hand just started to shake.
这是这些关节炎药的副作用
It's a side effect of these arthritis pills.
会读标签吗
Read the label.
在我把它打出来的时候看到了
I did... when I was typing it up,
然后把它贴在了一瓶糖罐上
right before I slapped it on a bottle of sugar pills.
你打了张假标签
You printed a fake label
就为了证明我是疑病症患者吗
just to prove I'm a hypochondriac?
有效吗
Did it work?
有效地把你自己给炒了  你个蠢货
It got you fired, you schmuck.
我花了一个小时才让她妥协配合考夫曼医生
An hour to convince her to go with Dr. Kaufman,
还只因为他主治的是内科
and only then because he runs internal medicine.
她都不想待在这家医院了
She wanted to leave the hospital entirely.
上帝  身体好转的女士
My God, a woman getting better
干嘛不想出院
wants to leave the hospital?
如果她真是有所好转  那也不是因为
If she's getting better, it's not because you made her
-你把她当傻子耍  -还能因为什么
- feel like a fool. - It couldn't be more because.
如果我没那么做  她会自我诊断出
If I hadn't, she'd have diagnosed herself
六种新式肿瘤
with six new forms of cancer.
她就永远出不了院了
She'd never leave.
应付我生病的母亲已经够我烦的了
It's hard enough dealing with my mom being sick.
你的这种幼稚行为
This juvenile--
请说
Yeah?
丽莎  你先别紧张
Lisa, it's gonna be okay,
-她出现心房颤动  心率升至170次  -天
- but she's in a-fib at 170. - Oh, God.
我觉得我们得趁她没昏倒前做心脏复率
I think we should cardiovert while she's unsedated.
我马上就过去
I'll be right there.
房颤  心率170
A-fib's at 170.
等等
Wait.
很抱歉她真的病了
I'm sorry she's sick.
但我下岗了可不是我的错
I'm not sorry I'm off the case.
你没下岗
You're not off the case.
你不会以为你能说服她...
You don't think you can convince her--
当然不  你继续跟进
No, no. You are staying on.
她不知道就成
She just can't know about it.
早上好  考夫曼医生
Top of the morning, Dr. Kaufman.
你看这样如何
Here's the deal.
你把所有图像拷给我
You copy me on all the imaging.
-我来让我的人做测试  -不
- I'll have my guys run the lab tests. - No.
我以为你已经跟卡迪交流过了
I thought you spoke to Cuddy.
没错  我又跟年长版卡迪交流了下
Yeah. Then I spoke to the elder Cuddy,
她特别强调不要让你参与进来
who specifically requested you not be involved.
听着  考考  你完全能胜任你的工作
Listen, Kauffy, you are perfectly competent,
几乎算得上不错了
bordering on good, even.
不过你知道我更出色
But you know I'm better.
当然你可以把这归结为
If you want, we can pretend it's 'cause
我有团队和资源优势
I got a team and more resources.
不管怎样  无视我的建议都太疯狂了
Either way, it'd be crazy to ignore my advice.
你不会满足于只提些建议的
It's not gonna stop at advice.
你会把我排除在外
You're gonna start cutting me out,
背着我去找你女朋友商量
go behind me to your girlfriend.
而一旦有什么差池
And if something goes wrong,
我还得独自面对医疗事故调查
still me standing up there alone at the M&M.
求你了...
Please...
离我病人远点
Stay away from my patient.
哪个按钮
Which button?
你右手那个
The one by your right hand
挨着床还有上下
with the design of the bed next to it and the arrows
-指示箭头的那个  -你安了窃听器
- pointing up or down. - You bugged the room?
我问心无愧地承认
I absolutely, without apology, will admit
某人确实这样做了
that someone may have allegedly done so.
看来我们从不道德直接转为违法了
Guess we can pass unethical and skip straight to illegal.
详情请参加高法最新案例
Not according to the recent Supreme Court case
"不服来咬我啊"
of bite versus me.
考夫曼医生还是单身
Dr. Kaufman's single.
你知道他是哈佛医学院毕业的吗
Did you know he went to Harvard Medical School?
妈  您就消停一会儿行不行
Mom, stop yenta-ing for one minute!
如果你喜欢阴郁的调调和不敢负责的软蛋
If you want gloomy and unable to commit,
你就和那异教徒混在一起吧
then stick with the goyishe one.
这真不道德  我们为啥要听这些
This is completely unethical. Why are we listening to this?
我知道我很烦  但是我没办法
I know I'm a pain, but it's impossible
-和你们共事如果...  -好吧好吧
- for me to work with you if you-- - Fine, fine!
就算不听现场  我二十分钟后也会
Instead of a live stream, I'll get a recap from Cuddy
从卡迪那知道的--谢谢你拯救了美国
20 minutes later-- thank you for saving America.
可能是白血病
Could be leukemia.
肿瘤侵袭骨髓导致贫血
Anemia from taking over the marrow,
肿瘤侵袭心肌导致房颤
a-fib from infiltrating cardiac muscle.
听上去不错
Sounds good.
是啊
Yeah.
我其实希望有别的诊断
I was really hoping for a different diagnosis--
某个考夫曼还没想到的
One that Kaufman hadn't already come up with.
他刚开始做骨髓活检
He just started a bone-marrow biopsy.
-那我们就什么都不用做了  -我不用
- So we don't need to do anything. - I don't.
但你用  去住院部给我们找个新病例来
You do. Go to admitting. Find us a new case.
过来
Psst! Whaa!
鉴别诊断
Ddx.
我们刚做完
Um, we just did it.
不  我们刚做了个假的
No, we just did the fake one.
知道我干嘛让真理仙子知道窃听器的事吗
Why do you think I let the truth fairy know about the bug?
我在考验她  她没通过
I was testing her. She failed.
她还跟缉毒刑警一样
She's still a narc.
硫胺素缺乏症比白血病更符合
Thiamine deficiency fits better than leukemia.
你觉得她是个酒鬼
You think she's an alcoholic?
我和艾琳娜吃过饭  我想给她杯金汤力
I had dinner with Arlene. I mixed her a gin and tonic.
不过我正好没汤力酒了
And I'd run out of the tonic,
我就加了点安眠药
so I substituted sleeping pills.
第二天早上  她以为
Next morning, she assumed
她意识缺失是因为喝多了
the blackout was from the drinking.
有多少老妇人会习惯于
How many old ladies are used to
喝晕过去
passing out from boozing?
只有酒鬼
The answer is the boozers.
我们得偷偷给她吃点硫胺素
We're gonna have to slip her the thiamine pills.
那我们得跟卡迪说一声
We've got to run this by Cuddy.
我不正为这事儿烦着呢嘛
Why do you think I'm in such a bad mood?
酗酒
Alcoholic?
治疗方法简单  又安全
Treatment's very easy, safe.
其实就是些维他命药片嘛
It's literally a few vitamin pills.
不仅能修复心脏问题
It'll fix her heart,
还不会影响到考夫曼进行的活检
and it won't interfere with the biopsy Kaufman's running.
把它们放在抗酸药的药瓶里
Put 'em in an antacid bottle.
就告诉她是治胃病的
Just tell her it's for stomach problems.
我得问问她
I have to ask her about this.
当然  完全同意
Of course. Absolutely.
你问了  她否认
You'll ask. She'll deny.
你再问  她觉得被冒犯了
You'll push it. She'll get offended.
这和现在情况一模一样
You'll be exactly where you are now,
只不过想治她更难了
except it'll be harder to treat.
真是个绝妙的主意
You've absolutely got to do that.
她不会骗我的
I don't think she'll lie to me.
过去的五年中
She just spent the last five years
她差点就奔向南面墨西哥边境了
going south of the border down Mexico way.
我们是有问题  但是自从父亲过世以后
We have our issues, but since dad died,
只要直接问  我们都会实话实说的
we tell each other the truth when asked directly.
这点对我们很重要
It's important to us.
瘾君子没实话
Addicts lie.
我能跟妈单独聊下吗
Can I speak to mom alone?
为什么
Why?
你吓到我了  丽莎
You're scaring me, Lisa.
妈  我认为你的心脏问题是酗酒造成的
Mom, I think your drinking is causing your heart problems.
你是说那杯香槟  她要了...
Is this about the champagne? She ordered--
帕特茜和安妮跟我说上周
Patsy and Anne told me last week
你在博物馆午宴上喝多了
you lost control at the museum luncheon.
你居然背着我去问我朋友
You're talking to my friends behind my back.
我们是关心你  实话实说...
We are all concerned. Just tell me honestly...
你最近到底喝了多少酒
How much have you been drinking?
我也许是你的病人  但我还是你妈
I may be your patient, but I am still your mother.
我告诉你  我不是酒鬼
And I'm telling you I am not a drunk.
好吧
Okay.
这是治胃痛的
For your stomach pains.
如果再有那样的事
If something like that comes up again, just...
该做什么就做什么吧
Do what you need to do.
-不用告诉你吗  -是
- And keep you out of it?  - Yeah.
我现在畏首畏尾
I am being a coward,
这正是为什么医生不应该
which is exactly why doctors shouldn't treat
治疗自家人的原因
their own families.
恭喜
Congratulations.
你又对了
You were right, as usual.
打了你是我考虑欠佳
The hitting you was not optimal.
我那时正处理自己的离婚问题
I was going through my own divorce at the time.
我这些年一直在做心理治疗
I have had years of therapy.
现在我生气时
Now when I get mad,
我会做做深呼吸  攥攥压力球
I do some deep breathing, squeeze my stress ball.
我也算应得的
Hey, I kind of deserved it.
那肯定
That's for sure.
你看这样行不行
Here's the deal.
我是做医疗过失保险的
I do a lot of med-mal insurance.
我需要一个新的不作证专家
I need a new non-testifying expert.
我会给你个案例测试一下
I'll give you one case as a tryout.
你做得好我们就签协议
You kick ass, I put you on retainer.
平均一周15小时  一年的报酬五开头
Average 15 hours a week, it's 50 a year.
五什么
50 what?
当然是五万
You kidding? $50,000.
我接受
I'll take it.
你也没得讨价还价
You drive a soft bargain.
你得签保密协定
You got to sign an N.D.A.
当然
Sure.
这是...
Is this...?
这案子我就要处理完了
Uh, that's a case I'm about to settle.
我代表一家批萨外送公司
I rep a giant pizza-delivery company.
司机撞了个孩子  把他腿撞坏了
Driver hit that kid, messed up his legs.
还导致了微量脑出血吗
And gave him a microbleed in his brain, right?
什么  当然没
What? No.
这个小白点
This little white mark.
你的前任和那孩子的医生都查过了
Your predecessor checked, so did the kid's doctors.
我不知道那是什么  不过孩子没事
I don't know what that is, but he's fine.
也许  不过如果有任何疑问...
Probably. But if there's any doubt--
这个案子涉及数百万美元
It's a multimillion-dollar case.
我们两天内就要谈妥了
We're settling in two days.
别管它了  好吗
Lay off it, okay?
好  你说的对
Okay. You're right.
我不管了
I'm off.
她开始发烧了  38.9度
She spiked a fever. It's 102.
也就是说不是硫胺素缺乏症
That means I was wrong about the thiamine deficiency.
也不是酗酒
You were wrong about the alcoholism.
顶一个
True dat.
确实越来越像白血病了
It's actually looking more and more like leukemia.
考夫曼加急了活检  不是癌症
Kaufman rushed the biopsies. It's not cancer.
那还是有好的一面嘛...
So there's a bright side...
考夫曼也错了
Kaufman was wrong too.
-鉴别诊断  -好吧...
- Ddx. - Okay...
什么病把卡迪母亲变成了
What disease can turn Cuddy's mother
这位名叫斯图尔特的植物人呢
into a coma patient named Stewart?
狼疮
Lupus?
她妈妈不归我们管了  生活还得继续
We got fired from that case. We're moving on.
-我们早就下岗了  -那只是病人说的
- We were already fired. - By the patient.
这次卡迪放话了  这是真下岗了
This time by Cuddy, so it's real.
她终于意识到
She somehow realized that
她那不可行的做法
her completely unworkable system
确实不可行
was completely unworkable.
好了  随堂检测
Okay, pop quiz, hot shots--
我选植物人小斯不是没有道理的
I chose vegetable Stew for a reason.
给你们六十秒  没有提示哦
You got 60 seconds, no "Hintsies."
你不跟我们说话了吗
You're not gonna talk to us?
没错  你们要 -- 嘿
Exactly. You're gonna have to -- hey!
你可以啊
You're good.
这就是个测验吗
So this is just a test?
瞳孔静止扩张
Pupils fixed and dilated--
瘾君子
an addict,
被发现时身边有一瓶空的安眠药
found with an empty bottle of phenobarb next to him.
这有什么神秘的  服药过量而已
How is this a mystery? It's an overdose.
苯乙哌啶酮
Glutethimide!
去年开的药
Script filled last year.
可能造成类似瞳孔静止扩张却不会脑死亡
Could mimic fixed and dilated without the brain death...
但他只能自己好起来
Except he'll just get better on his own,
那我们为什么要接这病例
so why would you take this case?
因为豪斯不关心治疗方法
Because House doesn't care about the treatment
只要这病例有趣
as long as the case is interesting.
我抽点血
I'll do a blood draw
然后把苯乙哌啶酮加入到毒素检测当中
and put glutethimide on the tox screen.
真的吗
Really?
你觉得那病例有意思吗
You thought that case was interesting?
看来我们其实没下岗
Oh, guess we're still on Arlene.
还有其它方法能让马斯特斯别挡道吗
Aren't there other ways of keeping Masters occupied?
我的性骚扰学会表示无能为力
Not according to my sexual harassment seminar.
也许不是多疑病
Maybe it's not hypochondria.
她说她常起疹子
She said she gets a lot of rashes.
加上发烧
Add the fever--
听上去像免疫病  系统性红斑狼疮症
Sounds like autoimmune, S.L.E.
恭喜恭喜  你终于学会像半瓶醋直晃荡的
Congratulations, you can think exactly like
内科医生那样诊断病人
a semi-competent internist.
考夫曼正要开始给她用强的松
Kaufman's starting her on prednisone.
但她最先出现的是心脏问题
But the heart problems were first.
会不会是心内膜炎
Endocarditis.
听诊时没有杂音吗
With no murmurs?
通常晚期才会出现杂音
It's usually a late sign.
心脏超声显示瓣膜完全正常
Echo showed pristine valves.
只能说明其异常程度不高于仪器分辨率
Below the resolving threshold.
考夫曼用强的松治疗
Kaufman's prednisone
将抑制她的免疫系统  她也许会有生命危险
will suppress her immune system--could kill her.
你得告诉他有可能是心内膜炎
You got to tell him it's endocarditis.
去听听窃听器就知道了
Check the wiretap.
给他设计智力的家伙一直在跟他理论呢
His I.D. guy's been putting the same argument to him.
如果他说服不了他  你觉得我有可能吗
He can't convince him. You think I got a better shot?
那我们怎么办
So what do we do?
我们给她换药
We switch her meds.
去找点广谱抗生素的溶液
We get a solution of broad-spectrum antibiotics,
注射到一个标着"强的松"的输液袋里
stick it in an I.V. bag marked for prednisone.
考夫曼一天也去不了几次
Kaufman can only be there a few times a day.
告诉艾琳你是药剂科的  直接把药换了
Tell Arlene you're from the pharmacy, switch 'em out.
你疯了吗  把事情搞得太复杂了
This is nuts. This is way too complicated.
只是挂一袋点滴而以
It's hanging an I.V. Bag!
如果主治医生不知道给她用的是什么药
If the attending doesn't know what she's on,
出现用药反应的风险
the risk of drug reaction--
哪有什么风险  我们知道他下的所有处方
What risk? We know how he's treating her.
我们连窃听器都装了
We bugged the room.
这不仅仅涉及能不能掌握信息
This is not about information!
我们要做的事情违反医德  违反法律
We're talking ethical and legal violations
如此严重的错误  连你都应该觉得恶心
on a scale that should make even you puke!
她要死了
She's dying!
那我们也不能为了救她统统进监狱
That doesn't mean we should all go to jail to save her!
你现在情绪失控
You're losing control because...
因为病人是你丈母娘
this is your girlfriend's mom.
你要跟卡迪商量一下吗
You gonna run this by Cuddy?
不
No.
她说了不要牵扯到她
She said to keep her out of it.
该怎么办就直接去办
Do what we need to do.
我知道我要你们去干的事情
Look, I know what I'm suggesting
完完全全不靠谱
is completely screwed up.
这也是因为出现了现在这种
That's because this situation
彻底不靠谱的情况
is completely screwed up.
要么干  要么卷铺盖走人
Do it, or you're fired.
我们团结一致  他总不能解雇我们所有人
We stick together, he can't fire all three of us.
给我一本处方笺
Give me a prescription pad.
你要那东西干什么
Why are you doing this?
因为我觉得她得了心内膜炎
Because I think it's endocarditis,
而且我认为强的松会置她于死地
and I think the prednisone will kill her.
我忘带我自己的处方笺了
Now, I forgot my prescription pad.
我是不是人品有问题
Am I a horrible person?
我曾经因为义务参加志愿者活动而获奖
I used to win awards for volunteer work.
我曾经去危地马拉做腭裂修补手术
I went to Guatemala and fixed cleft palates.
可现在我们却躲在这儿  让奇斯承担风险
Now we're sitting back letting Chase do our dirty work.
我们选择不参与其中
We're doing the right thing--
-是对的  -我分不清对错
- stay out of it. - I don't know.
我好像对任何事情都无法分清对错
I don't know about anything anymore.
但现在那个小孩的事  瑞秋她兄弟
Then this thing with the kid, Rachel's brother--
那件事情你也别参和
Stay out of that too.
首先  放射科医生说没有出血
A, radiologists experts,
人家是专家  跟你不同
unlike you, said no bleed.
第二  你自己也不能断定
B, you yourself said it's probably not.
第三  你不是那个小孩子的医生
C, you've got no doctor-patient relationship.
第四  你会丢掉这份当顾问的工作
D, you'll lose your consulting job.
第五  你前妻会杀了你
E, your ex will kill you.
第六  我快数不过来了
F, I'm running out of alphabet here.
你干好了
You do it?
我正拿着输液袋往病房走
Had the bag, walking towards the room,
卡迪妹妹跟我打招呼  "奇斯医生你好"
and Cuddy's sister says, "Hey, Dr. Chase."
去年的一次慈善活动上我见过她
I met her at that charity event last year.
这事只能你们两个去干了
One of you two has got to do this.
那次我也在
I met Arlene at the same benefit.
这借口真不错
Conveniently.
省省吧  别指望我
Come on, don't ask me.
我都不知道我自己怎么想的  是不是
I don't even know if I believe it's endo--
该死  是瑞秋的兄弟
Damn it. It's Rachel's brother.
有个新案子  他想让我帮忙看看
He wants me to check out some new case.
这借口也很不错呀
Conveniently.
这是次试用机会  我需要这份工作
It's a tryout. I need this job.
我必须得去
I got to do this.
你打算撇下我们不管  临阵脱逃
So you're just gonna ditch us, run off,
去研究你那个案子
and work on some other case?
你是帝莫西的妈妈吧
Are you Timothy's mom?
-是呀  -我叫克里斯托弗·陶博
- Yeah. - My name is Christopher Taub.
我是普林斯顿普雷斯波罗医院的医生
I'm a doctor at Princeton Plainsboro.
我看过你儿子的病志
I saw your son's file.
我觉得他可能有一处小范围的脑出血
I think he might have a very small bleed in his brain.
等等  你说你看过他的病志
Wait, you-- you saw his file?
你怎么能知道我们的情况  我从没
H-how do you even know who we are? I never--
你儿子有可能因脑出血而死去
Your son could die of a brain hemorrhage.
今天他得去做个脑血管造影检查
He needs a cerebral angiogram today.
立即开车带他去医院  我在那儿等你
Get in your car and meet me at the hospital.
帝莫西  我们得去趟医院
Timothy, we're gonna go see the doctor.
一道脑筋急转弯
Another pop quiz.
换一袋点滴需要几个愚蠢的医生才能完成
How many idiot doctors does it take to switch an I.V.?
我们等的时间越长
The longer we wait,
强的松抑制她免疫系统的时间也就越长
the more the prednisone is gonna kill her immune system.
现在也别装什么药剂师了
Forget playing pharmacist.
丈母娘每天下午都要睡觉
Mom naps every afternoon.
在病房门口等着
Wait by the room.
等她睡着  想办法把妹妹支开
When she falls asleep, get the sister out somehow.
卡迪医生你好  有时间吗  我想跟你谈谈
Hi, Dr. Cuddy, is now a good time to talk?
我忙着呢
Not really.
你还记得你之前找我们去会诊
So, um, you know how you had us consulting
然后又禁止我们继续参诊的事吧
and then stopped having us consult?
你怎么还没走
Why are you still here?
我感觉你的禁令
Um, well, I think the stopping
似乎不起作用了
might have stopped.
豪斯让我负责一个奇怪的病例
House put me on this weird case
可已没有可用的治疗了
where there's no treatment--
我觉得他是在分散我的注意力
I think maybe to distract me.
而且他们最近行动很诡秘
Uh, and they've been acting odd.
我会去调查一下
I'll look into it.
谢谢你来告诉我
Thank you for coming to me.
我来是因为我担心他打算
Because I'm--I'm worried that he's switching
偷偷换掉你母亲的药物
your mother's medications.
我问过药剂科了
I checked with the pharmacy--
奇斯医生给我的昏迷病人开了强的松
Dr. Chase got prednisone and antibiotics
和抗生素  显然对他不起作用
for my coma patient, which wouldn't treat him,
但能用来治疗可以导致...
but could treat conditions that cause...
心衰的疾病
heart failure.
你让我别牵扯到你
You told me to keep you out of it,
我该怎么办就怎么办
do what I needed to do.
不然那话还有什么意思
What the hell did you think that meant?
我说的是  如果你要偷偷给她
I meant, like, if you had to slip her
喂几片维生素之类  当然可以
a few more vitamin pills or something.
现在这可是要出人命的
This is life-threatening!
是违法的
It's illegal.
我没想到你会做出这样的事来
I wasn't expecting something like this.
没想到是因为你故意不往那方面想
Only because you intentionally weren't thinking about it
因为你不想做任何艰难的决定
'cause you don't want to make any tough decisions.
你肯定是心内膜炎吗
Are you completely sure it's endocarditis?
这算什么问题
That's not a real question.
相比较而言  心内膜炎更符合她的症状
Endocarditis fits better than the alternatives.
我们想给她用正确的药  但遇到了点困难
We're having a little trouble hanging the right I.V.
最快的解决办法是请你来帮忙
The fastest way is with you help.
茱莉娅去哪儿了
Where'd Julia go?
她有一家子人等着照顾呢
She's got a family.
我也有一家子人要照顾呀
I've got a family.
三个孩子加一个老公  这才叫一家子
Three kids and a husband-- that's a family.
你对我的标准总是比茱莉娅高
You were always tougher on me than Julia.
-这是为什么呀   -我没有
- Why is that? - I'm not.
我还记得你逼着我去争取
I was thinking about when you made me run
学年纪念册的编辑职位  我根本不想去
for yearbook editor-- I didn't want to.
高三整整一年我没参加任何社交活动
I didn't have a social life my whole senior year.
你允许茱莉娅做任何她喜欢的事情
You let Julia do whatever she wanted.
我们一定要现在争论你高三的事情吗
We're debating 12th grade now?
就像现在跟那时候不一样似的
Like anything's changed.
丽莎  你到底想要什么
What do you want, Lisa?
你想让我告诉你我对你们的爱是一样的
Do you want to hear I love you both the same?
这是当然的
Of course I do.
好吧
Okay.
但每到这种时候
But times like this,
当我们吵架的时候  总让我感到
when we argue, it reminds me...
我跟她更合得来
I have more in common with her.
她对我更好
She's nicer to me.
我同样地爱你们两个
I love you both...
但我更喜欢她
But I like her more than you.
我给你打了三个电话
I called you three times.
我的电话没开
My phone wasn't exactly on.
我准备好在放射科送来血管造影报告后
I figure I'll be getting some angry calls
接到多通骂人的电话
once radiology sends back the angiogram.
结果已经送回来了
They already did.
在这儿呢
Here...
你看到的就是这个
This is what you saw.
是一处头骨的解剖变异
It's an anatomical variant of the skull--
这块骨头紧挨着一条血管
the bone in proximity to a blood vessel.
他没什么问题
There was nothing wrong with him.
这是第七个原因
That was reason "G."
对他来说  真是好消息
That's good news for him.
-肺子正常吗  -弥散性喘鸣音
- Lungs clear? -Diffuse wheezing,
胸闷  皮肤瘙痒
tightness, pruritis.
发生了过敏反应
It's an allergic reaction.
看起来像是  但这说不通呀
Looks like. Doesn't make any sense.
给他用着强的松呢
She's on prednisone.
她怎么可能出现过敏反应
How could she get an allergic reaction?
我把抗生素换掉了
I switched out the antibiotics,
重新给她用上了强的松  她呼吸正常了
put her back on prednisone-- her breathing's normal.
但房颤的症状又出现了  体温也变得更高
But the a-fib's back, and her fever's up.
过敏肯定是因为我们给她用的抗生素
Allergy's got to be due to our antibiotics.
考夫曼知道我们干的这些事吗
Does Kaufman know what we did?
-很好  -不  糟糕极了
- That's good. - No, that is terrible!
他不知道她情况变差是由于抗生素的原因
He doesn't know that she got worse on antibiotics,
所以现在他会考虑心内膜炎的可能
so now he's thinking endocarditis.
他会再一次给她注射
He'll put her back on the antibiotics
几乎让她窒息的抗生素
that almost suffocated her.
我们该怎么办
What do we do?
坚持到底
We push through this.
一切症状都是心脏引起的
It started in the heart.
心内膜炎依旧符合病情
Endocarditis still fits.
只是可能是由真菌引起的
It's just got to be fungal.
我们得把考夫曼开的抗生素换成
We have to switch Kaufman's antibiotics
两性霉素B
for amphotericin B.
我不知道你的判断是否正确  无所谓对错
I don't know if you're right. I don't care.
如果我们还要继续偷偷换药
But we are gonna end up killing this woman
而误导她的主治医生
if we keep confusing her attending
她早晚得被我们害死
with these secret meds.
我不管她的主治医生有没有被误导
I don't care about confusing the attending!
我只要这个病人
I want this woman--
我们现在讨论的已不是简单的抗生素了
We're not talking about simple antibiotics anymore.
两性霉素B本身就很危险
Amphotericin B is dangerous in itself.
它就是种毒药  所以才能杀死真菌
It's a poison. That's why it kills fungi.
会让她发烧  打寒颤
It'll give her fever, chills--
她已经有这些症状了
Which she already has,
正好可以帮助我们隐瞒
which will help us hide it.
我觉得我不能冒这么大的风险
I don't think I can take a risk like that.
那你最开始就不应该让她炒我鱿鱼
Well, then you shouldn't have let her fire me!
听着  你只要再去换一下她的输液袋
Look, all you have to do is switch the I.V.S again.
这样做已经出过一次状况了
This has blown up on you once already.
-他说得对  -是呀
- He's right. - Yep.
给你们惹上这样的麻烦  真对不起
I'm so sorry I got you guys into this.
你们可以走了
You should go.
-我是对的  -我知道
- I'm right. - I know.
我会照你说的做  可是
And I'll do it, but...
我同意  是真菌性心内膜炎
I agree. Fungal endocarditis fits.
但我们还是要告知你母亲
But we still have to tell your mother.
我不想告诉她  真的不想
I don't want to tell her, not at all.
但病人才是最重要的
But the patient is the highest priority.
我要把你从你自己的办公室里驱逐出去
I'm kicking you out of your office.
没错  就是你
Yes, you.
这里还不是她的办公室呢
This is not her office yet.
你敢透露给任何人
If you tell anyone,
我就让医学院开除你
I will get you thrown out of med school,
毁掉你的职业前途
and I will destroy your career.
我考虑过了
I've thought about that.
撒谎害我
Lying about me...
是没用的
won't work.
所有人都知道你的作风
Everybody knows your reputation.
没错
True...
可我用不着撒谎
But I won't have to lie.
在你那位昏迷病人厚厚的资料中
Buried in your coma patient's big, big file
有一张表
is a form that doesn't allow treatment
写着未经家属同意不得治疗
without the expressed consent of the relatives.
-等等  -你抽了他的血
- Wait... - You drew blood.
这可不止是医疗失误
And that's not just a screwup.
而是伤害罪
It's criminal assault.
-可你让我  -我没有  你该记得的
- But you told me - No. As you may recall...
你陷害我
You set me up?
为什么
Why?
因为这位病人对我至关重要
Because this patient is the highest priority.
你让她以为我隐瞒了她儿子的病情
You made her think i was hiding her son being sick!
她撕毁协议  还向律师协会告发我
She scuttled the settlement. She reported me to the bar.
我现在官司缠身
I got to deal with that crap now.
我要告你诽谤  侵权干扰
I will sue you for slander, for tortious interference,
用所有我能想到的手段毁了你
and anything else I can use to destroy you.
还有  瑞秋说她不想见到你
Oh, and my sister says stay out of her life...
你这败类
You failure.
五年的理疗白费了
Five years of therapy.
考夫曼医生
Dr. Kaufman?
我需要跟你和病人单独谈谈
I need to speak with you and the patient alone.
我要越过审查委员会
I'm skipping the credentials committee.
直接向州管理局
I'm going straight to the State Board
举报你的...
and reporting you for...
你所作所为如此恶劣
what you've done is so off the spectrum,
我都不知道该怎么形容
I don't know there's a specific name for it.
他好像是在跟你说话
I think he's talking to you.
马帝  冷静
Marty, calm down.
还有你  你更过分
And you--what you did is worse.
他是精神失常的疯子
He's an insane lunatic.
可你是院长啊
You're the Dean of Medicine!
我不许你再插手我的治疗
I want you off my case.
这就对了
That's exactly right.
别高兴得太早  你也给我走人
Don't get excited. You're fired too.
-什么  -只要我留在这家医院
- What? - I'll never get away from House or my daughter
就永远别想摆脱我女儿和豪斯
if I stay here.
把我转到普林斯顿综合医院
Transfer me to Princeton General.
妈
Mom...
你病得很重  而且极度气恼
You're very ill, and you're very angry.
你觉得现在
You really think now is the right time
做这种决定合适吗
to make a decision like this?
你欺骗背叛了我
You lied to me and betrayed me.
你觉得
Do you think I really care
我会在乎你的意见吗
what you consider a good idea anymore?
我去安排救护车
I'll get the ambulance.
高兴了吗
Happy?
怎么会这样
I can't believe it.
这是怎么回事
What just happened?
你刚刚害死了她
You just killed her.
你还怪我
Are you blaming me?
全都是因为你的傲慢自负
This is all because you're so arrogant,
是你刺激她炒掉你的
you goaded her into firing you!
事实上  我的错误是从被炒掉之后开始的
Actually, my mistakes started a little after that,
我错就错在同意了你的天才决定
when I agreed to your brilliant scheme
在被炒掉之后仍然越俎代庖
to keep me on the case after she'd fired me off it.
不这样她可能会转院
She would have left the hospital.
要你同意她才能转  就像刚才那样
Only 'cause you would have let her, like you did just now.
你以为我控制得了她
You think I can control her?
谁知道呢  都没见你试过
I don't know. I've never seen you try.
我从小到大都在跟这个女人斗争
I have been rebelling against this woman my entire life.
据我亲眼所见
Here's what I've seen.
她伤害你  你就跟我抱怨
She insults you, you complain to me.
宴会上我给她下药  你没告诉她
I drug her at dinner, you never let her know.
我们换她的药  也完全不让她知道
We slip her medicine, happens behind her back.
你从不违抗她
You never confront her...
这让我很生气
And it pisses me off.
你因为这些事生我的气
Are you taking this persally?
她一出院  必死无疑
She leaves, she dies.
总有一天
One day...
或者一周以后  或者一年以后
maybe a week from now, maybe a year from now,
你会认定是睡在你身边的这个人
you're gonna decide that the man sleeping next to you
害死了你母亲
killed your mother.
去把我的病人抢回来
Get me my patient back.
丽莎  你搞什么
This is really bad, Lise.
茱莉娅  对天发誓  我要叫保安了
I swear to God, Jules, I will call security!
之前我问你为什么对我不好
I asked you before why you were tough on me.
-我没有  -你有
- I wasn't. - You were.
我知道原因
And I know why.
你在我身上看到某些不同于茱莉娅
You see something in me that you didn't see in Julia
不同于你的东西
and you didn't see in you...
我有抱负  有头脑
a type of ambition, a type of brains.
所以你才苛求于我
That's why you rode me.
是你让我成为年鉴编辑  优秀毕业生
You made me yearbook editor, summa undergrad,
医学院荣誉学会成员
A.O.A. in med school.
只有在听我谈工作的时候
The only time I ever see light in your eyes
你的眼里才会有光芒闪过
is when you hear me talking about my job.
你不停地来门诊找我
The reason you keep coming to see me in the clinic
是因为你信任我
is because you trust me.
你信任我的医学判断
You trust my medical judgment.
以下是我的判断
So here it is.
转到普林斯顿综合医院
If you transfer to Princeton General,
他们态度会很好  可是你会死
you'll be treated well, and you'll die.
留下接受豪斯的治疗
If you stay here with House,
他会很恶劣  但你能活下去
you'll be treated badly, but you'll live.
妈  哪怕要扎破
I don't care if I have to slash the tires
急救站所有救护车的轮胎
of every ambulance in this bay, mom.
我也不会让你离开我的医院
I am not letting you leave my hospital.
1  2  3
One, two, three.
我来  妈你感觉怎么样
I got it. How you feeling, mom?
我有点儿头晕
I feel a little dizzy.
因为感染  你的心脏仍然虚弱
Your heart's still weak from the infection.
我们要给你静脉注射抗真菌药
We'll hang an antifungal I.V.
你这么能耐
If you're so great, how come
怎么混到连部门都没了
you're not running your department anymore?
妈  你跟谁说话呢
What are you talking about, mom?
-他自己告诉我的  -两天前
- That's what he told me. - Two days ago,
我说我不用管理自己部门
I said that I didn't have a department to run.
-那是讽刺  -不  不是
- I was being sarcastic. - No, you weren't.
有理  说话的人
Right, because people who are talking
都分不清自己有没有讽刺
can't tell if they're being sarcastic.
胡说  说话人当然清楚
That doesn't make any sense. Of course they can.
可你没有讽刺
But you weren't.
我爱艾罗德
I love A-Rod.
他如此的谦逊
He's so modest.
我极度敬佩他的那些
And I highly respect the paintings
半人半马自画像
he has of himself as a centaur.
问  我喜欢艾罗德吗
Question-- do I like A-Rod?
喜欢  虽然我不知道他是谁
Yes... Whoever he is.
她不能识别讽刺
She can't recognize sarcasm?
右海马旁回缺损
Deficit in the right parahippocampal gyrus,
说明发热之前中枢神经系统就有病变
which means CNS involvement before the fever.
心内膜炎的判断是错的
I was wrong about the endocarditis.
我感  感觉不到
I-I don't... I don't feel...
妈  妈
Mom? Mom!
心率170  护士
Heart rate 170. Nurse!
-帮帮忙  -我忙着呢
- Do something. - I am.
-豪斯  -发热是下丘脑症状
- House! - The fever was hypothalamic.
说明脑部和心脏病变  贫血  过敏
That means brain, heart, anemia, allergy.
-以上症状  你想会是什么  -我不知道
- You hear that, what do you think? - I don't know.
-有没有可能是重金属中毒  -不可能
- You think heavy-metal toxicity. - It can't be.
你用螯合剂治疗过铅中毒
You treated with chelation for lead.
她先是好转然后又恶化
She got better, then she got worse.
她中的毒一直没停过
She never stopped being poisoned.
你做什么
What are you doing?
你真想我停下解释吗
You really want me to stop and explain?
就在这里
There it is.
肌肉变黑了
The muscle's black.
-是坏疽吗  -金属沉着病
- Necrosis? - Metallosis.
她的人造髋关节磨损过度
Her artificial hip "Weared and teared" way too much.
是钴中毒
It's cobalt poisoning.
让奇斯订手术室
We need Chase to get an O.R.
我马上再做螯合治疗
I'm gonna start chelation again.
我以为你不想见我
I thought you didn't want to see me.
之前确实是  福曼给我打了电话
I didn't. Foreman called me.
我不知道你认为
I didn't know that you thought
那男孩脑部有出血
that little boy had a bleed in his head.
我哥再敢找你麻烦
I will kill my brother
我就杀了他
if he messes with you anymore.
为什么管我
What do you care?
克里斯
Chris...
你是个混蛋丈夫
You were a crappy husband...
但却是个好人
But you are a good person.
对你的解雇再次撤销
Once again, you are unfired.
为什么
Why?
即便知道会被医学院开除
You sold me out even though you knew
你还是坚持告发我
that you were gonna get thrown out of med school.
这一举动
That's just...
令人刮目相看
kind of impressive.
无论我是不是站出来挑战你
I keep my job if I stand up to you.
都不会丢工作
I keep it if I don't.
我
I...
不信
don't buy it.
卡迪以前护着我
When Cuddy was protecting me before,
是在保护一名医生
she was protecting a doctor.
现在她护着的是她男朋友了
She's now protecting a boyfriend.
医院不会一直坐视不管
The hospital's not gonna put up with that for long.
所以我需要你来保护我
So I need you to protect me
以防卡迪做出让自己后悔的事情
from doing something Cuddy will regret.
希望明早看见一个高兴的你
See you bright and late tomorrow.
妈
Mom...
还留着这个做什么
Why would you want to keep this?
我要把它挂在墙上
So I can mount it on the wall,
像驼鹿头那样做装饰
like a moose head.
网上说
It says here
钴中毒可能导致皮疹
cobalt can cause rashes,
晕眩和胃部不适
dizziness, and stomach problems.
还认为那些症状是我想象出来的吗
You still think I've been imagining the whole thing?
好吧  算你说得有理
Okay, you might have a point.
感觉如何
How do you feel?
我有一点儿头晕
You know, a little dizziness...
还有点儿疼
some pain.